Guide to the University of Chicago Division of the Humanities, Research Grants Records 1926-1944
University of Chicago Library
University of Chicago. Division of the Humanities. Research Grants. Records
1926-1944
1.5 linear ft. (3 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Division of the Humanities Research Grants Records contain correspondence, reports and summaries relating to grants given for specific research projects undertaken by the faculty of the Humanities Division of the University. Most of the grants were awarded by the General Education Board, the Rockefeller Foundation and the American Council of Learned Societies.
Information on Use
Access
No restrictions
Scope Note
The Division of the Humanities Research Grants Records contain correspondence, reports, and summaries relating to grants given for specific research projects undertaken by the faculty of the Humanities Division of the University. Most of the grants were awarded by the General Education Board, the Rockefeller Foundation and the American Council of Learned Societies.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
University of Chicago. Division of the Humanities; University of Chicago-History; Research grants; Research grants-United States; Education, Higher-Research; Education, Higher-Research-United States
INVENTORY
- General correspondence, summaries, etc. 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General correspondence, summaries, etc. 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- General correspondence, summaries, etc. 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- General correspondence, summaries, etc. 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- General correspondence, summaries, etc. 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- General correspondence, summaries, etc. 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- General correspondence, summaries, etc. 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- General correspondence, summaries, etc. 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Rockefeller Foundation Subsidy for Fluid Research, correspondence, reports, etc. 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- General Education Board Subsidy Fund, correspondence, reports, etc. 1926-1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Matching money (gifts) correspondence 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Humanities projects, summaries of 1934-1939 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Allen, P.S., "Medieval Latin Lyrics," 1927-1929 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Allen, P.S., "Byzantine Poetry," 1932 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Baskervill, C.R., "Shakespeare," 1928-1934 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Bentley, G.E., Transcription of the records of the parish of St. Anne's, London, 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Bonner, R.J. and Gertrude Smith "The Administration of Justice in Greece," 1930-1938 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Buck, D.C., Dictionary of Selected Indo-European Synonyms, 1927-1936 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Carnap, R., Symbolic Logic project, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Case, S.J. and G.J. Laing, "Religious Records of the Graceo-Roman World," 1932 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Chang, P.C., Series of Chinese Classics in English translation, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Comparative Philology Research, Miscellaneous projects, 1932-1936 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Craigie, W.A., Dictionary of American English, 1926-1935 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Craigie, W.A., Dictionary of American English, 1935-1937 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Craigie, W.A., Dictionary of American English, 1937-1944 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Crane, R.S., Critical edition of Goldsmith's Traveller and Deserted Village, 1928-1934 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Creel, H.G., Chinese Language project, 1935-1941 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Cross, T.P., Institute of Celtic Research project, 1925-1933 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Cross, T.P., "Grudriss of Early Irish Literature," 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Dargan, E.P., "Balzac and Modern Fiction," 1927-1933 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Goodspeed, E.J., Purchase of a 14th-century Greek manuscript of the Gospel of Mark (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Goetsch, C., German Dialect Studies, 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Gottschalk, L.R., Lafayette Papers project, 1930-1934 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Grabo, C.H. and M.J. Freeman, "Prometheus Unbound," 1932-1934 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Graham, W.C., Phoenician Dictionary, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Hartshorne, C., "Science and the Sensory Qualities," 1930-1933 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Haskell lectures (on Comparative Religion) (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Haydon, A.E., Teaching of Religion project, 1935-1939 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Jernegan, M.W., "Education in the American Colonies," 1929-1931 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Keniston, H., "Syntax of Castillian Prose," 1932-1936 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Manly, J.M., Chaucer project, 1927-1934 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Manly, J.M., Chaucer project, 1935-1940 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Morris, C.W., Project on the unpublished material from George Herbert Mead's lectures, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- New Testament Dept. Miscellaneous projects (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Nitze, W.A., "The Arthurian Romances," 1927-1937 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Northrup, G.T., "Gran Conquista de Ultramar," 1932-1937 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Parmenter, C.E., "Experimental Research in Romance Phonetics," 1927-1937 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Riddle, D.W., New Testament project, 1935-1937 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Sapir, E., "Study of Native American Languages," 1930-1932 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Sherburn, G.W., "Neo-Classical Poets," 1929-1935 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Shorey, P., "Studies in Greek Philosophy and Language," 1927-1934 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Stevens, D.H., Milton project, 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Taylor, A., "Studies in Folk-lore," 1927-1933 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Thompson, J.W., "History of Book Manuscripts before the invention of Printing," 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Thompson, J.W., "Knowledge of Latin possessed by the Laity in the Middle Ages," 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Ullman, B.L., "Humanism of Coluccio Salutati," 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Ullman, B.L. and C.H. Beeson "Classical Culture in the Middle Ages," 1927-1936 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Willoughby, H.R., "New Testament Iconography," 1932-1936 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Wilt, N., "History of Theatrical Productions in Chicago," 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous projects (Box 4, Folder 16)